Ahmad Ali

Full-stack Developer - London, UK. Portfolio: https://ahmad-ali.co.uk/

Email: ahmad.ali.uk14@gmail.com • phone: 07383164194 • GitHub: https://github.com/ahmad-ali14 LinkedIn: https://github.com/ahmad-ali14

SUMMARY

I'm a Full-Stack Developer with 1 year of experience. I coded more than 50K lines, and I also assist in teaching a full-stack javascript course at CodeYourFuture. I'm educated up to degree level and I've finished more than 35 online courses. I'm currently studying computer science at UoPeople university. And I used to be a pharmacist.

EXPERIENCE

Code Your Future, London— Full Stack Developer April 2020 - PRESENT

- Teaching students a full-stack 8-month long course.
- Building the internal infrastructure which contains more than 6 apps that support and organise more than 1000 students and volunteers in more than 10 cities around the world.
- Added features to the API in node.js and MongoDB.
- Transformed parts of Dashboard into React Hooks.
- Created projects or challenges so the students can work on them as homework. Reviewed students code and gave them advice following the best practices.

Freelancer, London— Freelance Web Developer April 2019 - April 2020

- Developed, Designed and Deployed websites and online shops for clients.
- Maintained responsive products with security standards and basic SEO.
- Directly dealt with clients and adjust products according to their needs
- Provided technical training and after-sale support to my clients.

Pharmacist, Syria— Baylasan Pharmacy November 2016 - april 2018

Full-time job, handled prescriptions and gave medical advice to patients.

VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE

- Science Translator Arabic / English -at- I Believe In Science, Lebanon, Remote Freelance volunteer 1 year.
- Social Media Marketer -at Mind and World, Syria Freelance 2 years.

SKILLS

Javascript, React.js, Node.js, MongoDB, SQL, Html, CSS, bootstrap, jquery Rest API, git, npm, Docker, Php, WordPress, WP API.

Responsive web design, eCommerce, money-handlers integration.

PROJECTS

Hex Luxury LTD April 2020

- Hex is a luxury home accessories brand based in London.
- The project is an Online shop that sells 20 products.
- Built on WordPress and woo-commerce. Go-cardless money handler integrated.
- Basic SEO has been applied.
- Best security & performance practices have been applied
- Visit: https://hexltd.co/

Roye Interiors LTD December 2019

- Roye Interiors is an Interior Design company based in London.
- The project is an online portfolio shows the company projects and represent their values.
- Built on PHP and pure HTML with the help of CSS frameworks.
- Visit: https://roveinteriors.com/

Other projects

- My Portfolio my official website (MERN stack, REST API).
- **Dg-URL** npm library works with URLs (node.js).
- <u>Prfl20</u> elegent wordpress theme (php, WP_API).
- **E-Cart** e-commerce app (MERN stack, stripe).
- <u>Social-o</u> social media app (serverless, Firebase, React, Redux)
- Online video subtitles Editor add, update video file subtitles (React, Redux)
- List of all projects: https://www.ahmad-ali.co.uk/projects

EDUCATION

University of The People, USA — Computer Science 2020 - PRESENT

- Online, part-time. Will not affect my job.

Kiron Open Higher Education, Germany — Associate Degree in Computer Science 2018 - 2020

Free Code Camp, Online — Full Stack Developer BootCamp 2019

Damascus University, Syria — Bachelor degree in pharmacy and pharmaceutical chemistry 2011-2016

RECENT ONLINE LEARNING

- Introduction to Software Product Management, University of Alberta Coursera.
- Algorithmic Toolbox and data structures, University of California San Diego Coursera

REFERENCES

Available upon request